# William Hubenschmidt

https://hubenschmidt.github.io

## ABOUT ME

Newly minted full stack web developer with strong creative background and experience in relational database design, implementation, and management. Ten years experience in sales and fundraising roles. Specialties include programming languages, JavaScript (jQuery, Node.JS), relational databases, CRM, graphic design, audio engineering, video production and streaming, music theory, composition, writing, editing, and event management.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### 99¢ Dreams Records, 99¢ Radio, New York, NY

#### Executive Producer & Audio Engineer, August 2010-present

- Audio production; imagine and execute sound design; lead projects from development to execution; specialize in vinyl record and cassette production and dance music sales reaching international audiences in Europe and Japan, achieving airplay on BBC Radio 1 Essential Mix.
- Live stream internet radio and digital content management including design and code of www.99centradio.com; HD video encoding and high quality audio streaming; social media and streaming audio service integration
- Event production; booking, promoting, and executing local events featuring house and electronic music artists

#### Delivery Cyclist, New York, NY, November 2016-March 2019

 Slicing and dicing through the mean streets of Manhattan on a custom-built steel track bicycle. Provide professional courier services for private and app-based companies. More than 50,000 road miles logged

#### Nonprofit Fundraising Technology, New York, NY

## Consultant, January 2013-March 2016

- CRM database, web development, and fundraising for small business and mid-sized nonprofit clients including the
   Correctional Association of New York, Japan Society, James & Company, Color + Information, and Creative Connections, LLC.
- Co-authored "Why Every Nonprofit Needs CRM and How to Get it Right", a paper on best practices in database management and implementation in the nonprofit sector, published by Salsa (www.salsalabs.com).

#### Amnesty International USA, New York, NY

**Development Associate—Office of the Executive Director**, June 2012-January 2013

## Robert F. Kennedy Center for Justice and Human Rights, New York, NY

**Database Administrator**, May 2011-June 2012

- Database management: implemented and managed Salesforce.com database for three international offices.
- Co-launched RFK Young Leaders, a young professionals' network to empower human rights activists and defenders; managed outreach, volunteer, and fundraising activities. Managed event productions featuring Q-Tip (2012) and Questlove (2013) to raise more than \$100,000 for human rights education project.

AmeriCorps VISTA, Austin, TX and New York, NY
Grant Writer and Database Analyst, April 2009-May 2011

WCBN-FM, Ann Arbor, MI
On Air Disc Jockey, September 2007-April 2009

University Musical Society, Ann Arbor, MI

Programming Associate & Box Office Associate, September 2005-April 2008

#### **EDUCATION**

Columbia Engineering Coding Boot Camp, Columbia University, New York, NY, 2019 – Full Stack Web Development University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI, 2008 – B.A., American Culture/Music

whubenschmidt@gmail.com mobile: 347-909-0064